Guide to the New York Bureau of Legal Advice (New York Bureau of Legal First Aid) Records TAM.044
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: Case Files: Draft Boards, Aliens, Dependents
  - Hemizer, Isidor, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Herman, Morris, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hesser, Alex, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Himelstein, Herman, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Hirschman, Harry, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hogg, David, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Horowitz, Harry, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Hounkannen, E., 1918 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Howdale, Jack, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Hulnick, Abraham, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Hyman, Alex, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Hytonen, Lauri, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Immonen, Erick, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Inter, William, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Isenberg, Bernard, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Iverson, George, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    Reel 7006/8
  - J-General, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - K-General, 1917-1919 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Kato, K., 1918 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Kernieff, Tichon, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Kitchen, John, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Klatzin, Arthur, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Kok-Ason, Limson, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Krueger, William, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Kuller, Max, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - L-General, 1917-1919 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Laakos, Matti, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Leder, Julius, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Leibowitz, Sam, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Levey, Aaron, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Levine, Abe, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Levine, Kive, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Levine, Murray, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Levitan, Wolf, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Lumin, Samuel, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - M-General, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Mackenzie, Richard, not dated (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Mackie, Benjamin, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Maglio, San, 1917-1918 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Malerman, Nathan, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Malin, Israel, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Mallen, Raphael, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Malloff, Julius, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Mannarinn, Frank, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Mannen, George, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Marin, John C., 1917 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Melnick, Abe, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Mendick, Joe, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Mersitz, Julius, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Metz, Andrew, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Migny, M. A., 1918 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Milkens, Julius, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Miller, Isidore, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Miller, John, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Miller, Leo, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Miller, William, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Moccia, Nicola, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Moches, Hyman, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Mogul, Harry, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Montanino, Edward, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - N-General, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Nadler, Harry, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Nardone, Simone, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Neri, Vincenso, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Neuman, Max, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Nieman, William, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Nord, Alex, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - O-General, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Ojutkanga, A., 1917 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Oster, Jacob, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Owen, Harry, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - P-General, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Papleo, Emilio, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Paperman, Louis, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Pechenick, Joe, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Picker, Isidore, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Pitkowsky, Morris, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Polks, Hyman, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Polman, Morris, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Potashnick, S., 1918 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Poyourow, Julian, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Pratusch, William J., 1918 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Precepelia, Vladimir, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Press, Michael, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Proner, Charles, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Pucci, Bruno, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - R-General, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    Reel 7006/9
  - Redber, Abe, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Reich, Morris, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Reiss, Eugene, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Redenko, Frank, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Rolling, Bernard, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Rosen, Isidore, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Rosen, Murray W., 1917 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Rosen, Samuel, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Rosenblatt, Sam, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Rosenbloom, Morris, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Rosier, Harry, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Ruippe, Tobias, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Ruven, Joseph, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - S-General (Folder I, Saarela to Shonberger), 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - S-General (Folder II, Siegel to Szathmary), 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Sachs, Jack, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Salo, Kaarlo, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Salovaara, Hjalmar, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Salvatore, Giordano, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Saltz, Jack, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Sammet, Max, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Schady, William, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Schildcrout, Rubin, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Schloimovitz, Morris, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Schneiderman, Julius, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Schneiderman, Rubin, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Schor, Jacob, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Schub, Morris, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Schwartz, Martin, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Schwartz, William, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Schwartzberg, Rubin, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Schwimmer, Abraham, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Scott, Hyman, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Seigel, Rubin, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Selis, Solomon, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Serota, Jacob, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Shapiro, David, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Shatchen, Michael, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Shmereloff, Isidore, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Siegel, Harry, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Simon, Sam, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Simon, Samuel, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Singer, Charles, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Suoyka, Vofrid, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Slutsky, Nathan, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Snitko, Steve, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Sobel, Jacob, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Solomon, Joe, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Solomon, Philip, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Sonnenshine, Louis, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Soodack, David, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Sorin, Louis, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Spagnulo, Santo, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Spahn, Max, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Stepanoff, A., 1918 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Strauss, David, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Strauss, Moe, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Stronczer, Edward, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Strunin, Abe, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Sugar, Jacob, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Swidler, Sidney, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Swititsky, Charles, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - T-General, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Tabachnik, Abraham, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Teutelbaum, Morris, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Trolin, Morris, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - U,V- General, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Vandelwitz, Morris, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Van der Linden, Johannes, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Vuareggi, Washington, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Vichinsky, Osip, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - W-General, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Wassaur, Emil, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Weichman, Isidore, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Weinstein, Benjamin, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Weiss, Eugene, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Weiss, Max, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Weizel, Isidore, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Weiner, Isaac, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Williams, Elmer, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Wilson, John, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Witkowski, Stanley, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Walchok, Samuel, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Wolson, Lewis, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Wujcik, Frank, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Y-General, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Yanowitz, Harry, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - Yoches, Charles, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - Z-General, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Zelker, Benjamin, 1917-1918 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Zelnik, Eddie, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - Znack, Andrew, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Zucker, Morris, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Zucker, Sydney, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 61)
- Series VI: Press Releases and Newspaper Clippings
  Most of the clippings collected here come from articles in The Call or The New York Times. Topics range from free speech issues to amnesty of conscientious objectors to deportation legislation.
  - New York Bureau of Legal First Aid - Press Releases, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - New York Bureau of Legal First Aid - Press Releases, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - New York Bureau of Legal First Aid - Press Releases, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - New York Bureau of Legal First Aid - Press Releases, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - New York Bureau of Legal First Aid - Newspaper Clippings: includes everything regardless of subject, in which the Bureau is mentioned, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Reel 7006/10
  - Army - Complaints of soldiers of ill treatment, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Army - Conscientious Objectors, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Army - Court Martial-Agitation, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Army - General: Includes court martial cases but not court martial agitation. All Conscientious Objectors material is in Army- Conscientious Objectors file., undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Debs - Nearing - O'Hare, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Deportation - Agitation and legislation. Move for deportation of Soviet Bureau under file of that name., undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Deportation - cases, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Enemy Aliens, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Espionage Act - Agitation for repeal and amnesty, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Espionage Act - Cases (Special folder for Debs, Nearing and O'Hare), undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Foreign Countries, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Free Speech - General: Includes Free Speech Cases except under new gag laws, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Free Speech - Hall Boycott against radicals, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Immigration - Bills, editorials, etc., undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - I.W.W. - Includes matter on I.W.W. not in Deportation or Lusk Committee Folders, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Lusk Committee, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Lusk Committee - Raid on Rand School, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Lusk Committee - Raid on Soviet Bureau, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Lusk Committee - Unions, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Peace Time Sedition Laws (Federal and local) - Agitation, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Peace Time Sedition Laws (Federal and local) - Cases, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Political prisoners - General and Amnesty, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Soviet Bureau - All matters on the Soviet Bureau except Lusk raid, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Violence - General, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Violence - Raids on radicals and spying organizations. Includes all raids except Lusk Committee and May Day, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)